Victoria Vela

Software Engineer

(214) 334-7890 · victoriavela01@gmail.com · Rogers, AR · in/victoria-vela1 · github.com/vvela2022

I'm a software engineer with a background in sales who is energized by collaborating with team members to solve complex problems. I have a strong passion for improving user experience and am energized by delivering technology based solutions.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, | **Databases** - Relational (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB) **Libraries and Frameworks** - React JS, Express.js, Bootstrap, Materialize

Other - RESTful Routing, MVC architecture, object-oriented-programming, version control

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Gift Planner An application for housing gift ideas

- Single-handedly built a full stack Python/Django application with full CRUD and User Auth functionality.
- Used a relational database; PostgreSQL to implement a one to many relationship allowing users to add many gift ideas to their respective boards
- Utilized Materialize framework and Flexbox to create a polished front end user interface.

Books2Read | App to browse and find your next book to read

- Developed a React JS application with functional components utilizing the New York Times Books API
- Leveraged React Router and Integrated third party API calls into application to send GET requests
- Created a responsive, mobile friendly layout utilizing custom CSS (Flexbox, media queries)

LandPost | App for travel bloggers

August 2022

- Developed a Full-Stack Express app for travel bloggers using the MEN (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express.js, Node.js) stack to handle full CRUD operations
- Collaborated with two other software engineers to plan and build out application utilizing version control and regular check-ins to ensure we hit our deadline
- Implemented User Authentication and Authorization in backend as well as Flexbox on front end to enhance the user interface

War Card Game | A browser based card game

July 2022

- Utilized HTML, CSS, & JavaScript to develop a web-based card game
- Implemented JavaScript for game logic such as card shuffle, war, and win/loss functionality. Implemented DOM manipulation to render the game in user-friendly format
- Applied a dynamic layout using **Flexbox** to control the user interface of the application

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Mills, Customer Account Manager (Albertsons) | Rogers, AR

January 2022 - June 2022

- Partnered with Albertsons corporate buying team on strategic objectives through regular touchpoints and strategy sessions
- Grew distribution and dollar share by working with cross-functional teams to create and execute winning plans
- Maintained up to date forecasts which resulted in achieving our budgetary and sales volume goals
- Utilized syndicated data to influence merchandising and distribution decisions at Albertsons resulting in YOY sales growth

- Collaborated with cross functional partners to develop plans that drove annual distribution and dollar growth
- Partnered with broker to drive strategic initiatives through to the retailer store level
- Delivered volume, distribution, and budgetary and budgetary goals

General Mills, Trade Planning Lead (HEB, Meijer, Publix) | Tampa, FL

February 2018 - October 2018

- Managed the centralized planning team on the Cereal business unit
- Supported customer teams by providing trade, volume, and forecasting strategies and solutions
- Utilized syndicated data to create sales decks for customer teams to leverage resulting in distribution gains on shelf.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

July 2022 - October 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

University of Arkansas, Sam M Walton School of Business | Fayetteville, AR

Graduated 2013

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration (Marketing)